Raphael Wagner

☐ +49 1590 6187269 ☑ raphael.wagner@mail.de 😯 raphael-wagner.netlify.app/

PhD student in Mathematics at Ulm University

Discussing interesting problems with students and other researchers has helped me become an effective communicator and has made me value the joy and strength of working in a team of bright and intelligent people. Simultaneously, my experience in academia has also equipped me with a good amount of stubbornness and determination to overcome challenges, along with the ability to work independently. With a minor in Computer Science and a past internship as a software developer, I am confident in my programming skills.

Education

Ulm University Ulm, DE

PhD student in Mathematics, expected to graduate in winter 2023/24

09/2020 - present

• Research topic: Statistical concepts in mathematical fluid mechanics

Ulm University

Ulm, DE

M.Sc. in Mathematics, minor in Computer Science

10/2017 - 08/2020

• Final grade: 1.0 with distinction (1.0 - 5.0 with 1.0 being best)

Syracuse University Syracuse, US

M.Sc. in Mathematics

08/2018 - 05/2019

• Final grade: A (A – F with A being best)

• Double degree program with Ulm University, supported by a Fulbright travel grant

Ulm University Ulm, DE

B.Sc. in Mathematics and Management

10/2014 - 10/2017

• Final grade: 1.2 (1.0 - 5.0 with 1.0 being best)

Work Experience

Ulm University Ulm, DE

Scientific assistant

09/2020 - present

- Creating weekly assignment sheets, administering the grading thereof and presenting the corresponding solutions in an auditorium
- Organizing recitations for one or two classes each semester

Kistler Chemnitz GmbH (formerly AMS GmbH)

Chemnitz, DE

Internship as Java software developer

07/2017 - 01/2018

- The AMS GmbH was specialized in developing software for the analysis and management of measurement data the company has been acquired in December 2018 by the Kistler Group, a global leader in dynamic measurement technology
- Created a specific component for a customer within the company's framework jBeam that determines optimal machine parameters based on entered test data

Extracurricular activities

Association of Applied Mathematics and Mechanics (GAMM)

Ulm, DE

Junior member of the GAMM Student-Chapter Ulm

06/2022 - present

• Interdisciplinary network for students and researchers from applied mathematics and mechanics

Promovierendenkonvent Ulm University

Ulm, DE

Elected member

10/2022 - 10/2023

• Official council at Ulm University representing the interests of the doctoral students

Skills & Interests

Languages: German (native), English (fluent)

Programming: Java, Python (machine learning applications), Matlab, R, SQL

Interests: Sports (Running, Hiking, Volleyball and ice skating), playing electric guitar and cooking